One of your first project tasks will be to create containment features.
你的第一个实战项目任务是创建包含系数特征
Here's the equation for calculating containment.
这是包含系数的计算公式
Let's go over each term one by one.
我们看看每项的含义
You'll first see a few of this word ngram.
首先是多次出现的 ngram
An N-gram is a sequential word grouping of length n words.
N 元语法是 n 个字词的序列组合
For example, in a phrase like,
例如在句子
''I like to read books.''
“I like to read books.”中
A 1-gram or unigram is just one word like ''to'' or ''read''.
一元语法是指一个字词“to”或“read”
A 2-gram might be ''like to'' or ''read books'' and a 3-gram might be ''like to read''.
二元语法可以是“like to”或“read books”三元语法可以是“like to read”
In this project, you'll be comparing a source text S and an answer text A,
在此项目中 你需要比较原文 S 和答案 A
trying to see if the answer text is plagiarized from the source or not.
看看答案是否剽窃了原文
Thinking about n-grams, you might intuitively say that the
对于 N 元语法 可以直观地得出结论
more n-grams that the two texts have in common,
两段文本相同的 n-gram 越多
the more likely it is that the given answer text was plagiarized from the source.
答案越有可能剽窃了原文
Containment is a mathematical way of representing
包含系数就是这种概念的数学表示方式
this idea and it's easiest to see in an example.
举个例子比较好理解
Consider these examples sentences, the answer,
假设有两个句子
''This is an answer text,'' and the source,
答案是“This is an answer text.”
''This is a source text.''
原文是“This is a source text.”
Say we have an n of 1, which means,
假设 n 为 1
we're going to look at every word in an answer text and every word in a source text.
表示我们将查看答案和原文里的每个字词
We'll count up the occurrences of each word in each text.
我们将统计每个字词在这两段文字里的出现次数
This gives us the n-gram counts.
得出 n-gram 计数
Then we'll take the intersection of those n-gram counts.
然后查看这些 n-gram 计数的交集
The intersection is the set of n-grams that both of the texts have in common.
交集是指两段文字都具有的 n-gram 集合
Here, we see that both of the texts contain the words,
可以看到 两段文本都具有字词
This, Is, and Text.
This is 和 text
This is the intersection.
这就是交集
To get a numerical value that represents this intersection,
要计算表示这种交集的数值
We just sum up these occurrences to get the value 3.
只需将这些次数相加 得出值 3
Finally, we'll normalize this value by dividing by
最后归一化该值
the sum of all n-gram counts in the answer text.
即除以答案里的所有 n-gram 计数的和
For an n equal to 1,
如果 n 等于 1
this is 5 for the five words and we get the final containment value 0.6.
这个为 5 表示五个字词 最终包含系数为 0.6
So to summarize, we calculated the number of
总结下 我们计算了
n-grams that the source and answer text have in common,
原文和答案中都有的 n-gram 的数量
then divided that value by the number of n-grams in the answer text.
然后除以答案文本里的 n-gram 的数量
A value of 0.6 is quite high,
值 0.6 很高了
but maybe it's just because these texts are
但也许是因为这些文本很短
short or they use the same kind of filler words.
或者使用了相同的填充词
Now, if we selected an N equal to two,
如果 n 等于 2
we would look at which pairs of words these texts have in common.
我们将查看这两段文本中的哪些字词对一样
With an N of 1, the order of words didn't matter.
n 等于 1 时 字词顺序不重要
But with a larger N, the order of words in each n-gram does matter.
但是如果 n 更大 每个 n-gram 中的字词顺序很重要
Consider a longer text.
对于更长的文本
You can imagine that if you have a high containment value
如果二元、三元或更长语法的
for matching two grams or three grams or longer,
包含系数很高
then this might be a good indicator of cut and paste style plagiarism.
那么表明可能存在复制粘贴剽窃行为
This will be one of the features that you calculate for our corpus of
这将是我们的文本语料库中需要计算的一个特征
text data and you'll get more practice calculating containment next.
接下来你将进一步练习如何计算包含系数